I'm going to show you how to clean your
Ninja Creamy after each spin. So, the
parts that you're going to have to
clean, you're going to have your blade
attachment that goes on top of the bowl.
This is going to be the most dirty
thing. You got to get this in the sink
right away. This also usually needs a
wash. Sometimes it's fine, but I'm going
to rinse this as well. Obviously, your
dispensing area, since I'm filming,
takes a little more cleaning than what
you might have to do. The only other
thing you have to do with the machine
itself, so this is what's called the
spindle. This is the part that actually
powers the blade and actually spins the
ice cream. So, it gets heavily used in
each spin. It's often going to be
covered in the leftover ice cream. So,
since this was a brownie batter one,
it's like very dark. Um, so I usually
come in here with a paper towel and try
to wipe off as much as I can, getting
the top as well. You just want to wipe
this down at least every time you spin
it. Sometimes you're going to want to
come in and give it a deeper clean, but
you can see like tons of stuff gets on
it. So, you definitely need to clean
this every time. I know a lot of people
don't. And then the grooves are the hard
part to clean. So, either I like to get
in there with like my fingernail or what
I've been doing lately is I'll grab
Let's grab a new paper towel. That's
kind of gross. And then a toothpick,
right? And then you're going to put the
paper towel in front of the toothpick.
And then use the toothpick to kind of
guide the paper towel. And that'll get
in between the grooves very well. And
you can get like whatever's in the
grooves. You know, it's it gets kind of
dirty. Like I don't do this every single
time, but I would say
at least once a month. Really only have
to clean a few things, right? We have
the bowl. This is a little bit dirty.
Definitely worth rinsing. And then of
course the spinning paddle with the
blade and this outer ring. So what I
start by doing, so you can also do this
all in the dishwasher, but you
definitely want to rinse it first. Um,
start by just completely rinsing it. At
least just get all that initial ice
cream off. Then you're going to dispense
the blade by pushing this up and then
the blade will pop out. And then you're
going to want to rinse this as well. Ice
cream gets in there all the time. I give
that a good rinse. Get some soap in
there. The ice cream doesn't lodge up in
this thing quite as much as other parts.
So, this just needs like a little rinse.
But then also from this top, you're
going to get this ring out. Super easy
to get out. You just grab the top and
then this ring. Sometimes ice cream gets
stuck up like in these little grooves.
So, I like to just give it a quick once
around with a sponge.
Like I said, you can do this in the
dishwasher if you want. So, then that's
clean. Then back to the top. A lot of
gunk does get stuck in the crevices of
this thing, so you want to get some soap
in there. Just rub it down as good as
you can. And then what I like to do is
push the blade dispenser down so you can
get into this part and just get some
soap in there. Get some water in there.
And then the bowl. Super easy. Just nice
rinse, good scrub,
and then that's it. And obviously
you have your Ninja Cream pint. I'm just
recording this video before I eat this,
which is kind of ass because I want to
eat it and it's so good. Look at that.
This too, just give that a rinse. Use
some soap. My only other tip is to
occasionally soak all of your
attachments in a big bowl of soapy
water. So, I'll show you that now. So,
just fill up a bowl soapy water. Get
some soap in there. And then you're just
going to throw all of your attachments
in. So, especially this one. And then of
course these two. You have the Ninja
Creamy Swirl. You'll also have this lid
which is for the soft serve dispenser.
This works the same way as the other
lid. So you just unlock it here. This
pops out. And then you have an outer
ring that you can take off just like the
other one. And this also has a bunch of
crevices that you want to look out for.
Keep very clean. We'll soak these as
well because it can never be too clean.
I like to do this about once a month
depending on how many times I use the
Ninja Creamy. And then you're going to
want to get something heavy just to
weigh it down. And then fill it up to
the top with more water. And that's
basically it. So if you want to clean
your Ninja Creamy properly, do all of
these things. Keep it clean. You don't
want to be eating weird mold and
bacteria. You definitely want to clean
it after every use and then every few
weeks or so do a deep clean on it. If
you guys want more tutorials like this,
let me know. I'm happy to make whatever
you guys need, whatever you guys are
curious about the Ninja Creamy. So, take
this as your sign to clean your Ninja
Creamy cuz I know you haven't been
cleaning it regularly and you really